# MAHMOUD HIJAZI

Fullertony, CA 92831

Phone: 949.378.6274 | Email: hijaziii@hotmail.com LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:bit.ly/3nsjsFs">bit.ly/3nsjsFs</a> | GitHub: github.com/hijaziii | Portfolio:

hijaziii.github.io/Personal--Portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Management and Economics. Recently finished a 24-week intensive program at UCLA to upskill as a Full Stack Web Developer and engaged in a multitude of projects acquiring practical experience in the field. Known among my class to be determined to excel at learning and applying technology to practical business use-cases.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Frameworks: Node. js, Express.js, React.js, Redux, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Materialize,

Semantic UI

Databases & Tools: MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku, Git, OAuth, Postman

#### **PROJECTS**

**Lunde Water** | https://github.com/dmlunde/hydrohomies | lunde-water.herokuapp.com

Lunde Water (Continuation under DataSlate L.L.C.)

https://github.com/dmlunde/hydrohomies | lunde-water.herokuapp.com

KAMPers Visitors Management System | https://github.com/koyeary/KAMPers | kampers-vms.herokuapp.com

California Parking Services | github.com/hijaziii/California-Parking-Services | hijaziii.github.io/California-Parking-Services

#### EXPERIENCE

**Junior Full Stack Developer** DataSlate L.L.C.

01/2021 - 03/2021Los Angeles,

California

I had the opportunity to upgrade Lunde water project under DataSlate as a contractor

Full Stack Developer (Volunteer) **International American University**  07/2020 - 09/2020Los Angeles,

California

I started working with the American International University as a volunteer to continue to develop and progress my skills as a Full Stack Developer. I worked with a team of 3 to help develop a touchless visitor management system using the MERN stack.

Key Accomplishments:

The new system that I helped develop allows customers to custom schedule appointments either online or on-demand onsite using video conferencing. Customers with appointments receive customized QR codes upon approval via email which grants them access to the building. The system also integrates with Google oAuth services for ease of registration & access. Reminders delivered via SMS & email services.

### Valet Manager California Parking Services

02/2009 – Current Los Angeles,

California

California Parking Services is a renowned valet parking agency used by major entertainment and sporting events throughout the Los Angeles area. My role as a supervisor of 20 consists of:

- Supervising attendants and coordinate operation of automobile storage garage and parking lot.
- Planning work schedules, assign duties and supervise workers' activities to ensure compliance with established rules and regulations.
- Maintaining a daily record of operations, including money received, services performed and accidents reported.

#### **EDUCATION**

## UCLA Coding BootCamp: Los Angeles, CA

03/2020 -

09/2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**SUNY Empire State College:** Saratoga Springs, NY

2003 - 2008 (Transitioned from American University of Science and Technology, Beirut, Lebanon)

Bachelor of Science - Business and Management Economics